yesscotland.net 2014-06-28

# Yes Scotland privacy policy | Yes Scotland

Yes Scotland is an alliance of the Scottish National Party, Scottish Socialist Party and other groups and individuals who believe that is fundamentally better for all of us if decisions about Scotland’s future are taken by the people who care most about Scotland - that is by the people of Scotland. We treat the information supplied to us by our supporters and visitors with respect - and make sure that it is properly protected.

 **Data Protection Act**

The information you supply us will be treated with the strictest confidence in accordance with the Data Protection Act. Information may be stored on a computer database and used by the Yes Scotland alliance and its members to keep you informed of YES SCOTLAND news, campaign and other opportunities to support the campaign. If you prefer not to receive any future information, please contact us.

 **Joining the campaign online**

We collect the required information so that we can check whether you are located in Scotland. For example, we have a target of signing up 1 million Scottish voters for the Yes Declaration, and the information gather allows us to filter out people who do not meet the criteria. The information collected will also enhance your engagement with the site. Additional information such as gender and date of birth is provided at your discretion and will help us provide a better service to you.

 **Donating to Yes Scotland**

The information we ask for is used to process your donation and to enable us to meet anticipated legal restrictions on campaign donations for the referendum campaign

 **Links to other sites**

Our site contains links to other sites and servers. Yes Scotland is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

 **How we protect your information**

Our website has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. Our server is located in a locked, secure environment, with a guard posted 24 hours a day. When you contribute online, we use a secure server to protect your credit card number and other personal information during transmission. Credit card details remain encrypted until they are transferred to a computer not directly connected to the Internet.

 **Cookies in Use on This Site**

A cookie is a tiny text file that is stored on your computer. We may use technology to track the patterns of behaviour of visitors to our site. This can include using this "cookie" file which would be stored on your computer. You can usually modify your browser to prevent this happening. We may store the Internet address you connect to our server with, the time and date you connected, browser information and the pages you visited. This information is used only to provide us with a broad statistical breakdown of our site usage and to monitor site security.

Our website uses cookies, as almost all websites do, to help provide you with the best experience we can. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer or mobile phone when you browse websites

Our cookies help us:

  * Make our website work as you'd expect
  * Save you having to login every time you visit the site
  * Remember your settings during and between visits
  * Improve the speed/security of the site
  * Allow you to share pages with social networks like Facebook
  * Personalise our site to you to help you get what you need faster
  * Continuously improve our website for you
  * Make our marketing more efficient (ultimately helping us to offer the service we do at the price we do)

We do not use cookies to:

  * Collect any personally identifiable information (without your express permission)
  * Collect any sensitive information (without your express permission)
  * Pass data to advertising networks
  * Pass personally identifiable data to third parties
  * Pay sales commissions
  * You can learn more about all the cookies we use below

 **Granting us permission to use cookies**

If the settings on your software that you are using to view this website (your browser) are adjusted to accept cookies we take this, and your continued use of our website, to mean that you are fine with this. Should you wish to remove or not use cookies from our site you can learn how to do this below, however doing so will likely mean that our site will not work as you would expect.

 **Website Function Cookies**

 **Our own cookies**

We use cookies to make our website work including:

  * Determining if you are logged in or not
  * Remembering your search settings
  * Allowing you to add comments to our site
  * Tailoring content to your needs
  * There is no way to prevent these cookies being set other than to not use our site.

 **Third party functions**

Our site, like most websites, includes functionality provided by third parties. A common example is an embedded YouTube video. Our site includes the following which use cookies:

  *  YouTube ([privacy policy](http://cookie.attacat.co.uk/policy_plain.php)) powers some of the videos on our site. 

Disabling these cookies will likely break the functions offered by these third parties

 **Social Website Cookies**

So you can easily 'Like' or share our content on the likes of Facebook and Twitter we have included sharing buttons on our site.

Cookies are set by:

  * Twitter - [Privacy Policy](http://cookie.attacat.co.uk/policy_plain.php)

The privacy implications on this will vary from social network to social network and will be dependent on the privacy settings you have chosen on these networks.

 **Anonymous Visitor Statistics Cookies**

We use cookies to compile visitor statistics such as how many people have visited our website, what type of technology they are using (e.g. Mac or Windows which helps to identify when our site isn't working as it should for particular technologies), how long they spend on the site, what page they look at etc. This helps us to continuously improve our website. These so called â€œanalyticsâ€ programs also tell us if , on an anonymous basis, how people reached this site (e.g. from a search engine) and whether they have been here before helping us to put more money into developing our services for you instead of marketing spend.

We use Google Analytics

 **Turning Cookies Off**

You can usually switch cookies off by adjusting your browser settings to stop it from accepting cookies (Learn how here). Doing so however will likely limit the functionality of our's and a large proportion of the world's websites as cookies are a standard part of most modern websites

It may be that you concerns around cookies relate to so called "spyware". Rather than switching off cookies in your browser you may find that anti-spyware software achieves the same objective by automatically deleting cookies considered to be invasive. Learn more about [managing cookies with antispyware software](http://www.attacat.co.uk/resources/cookies/how-to-control-your-online-privacy).

The cookie information text on this site was derived from content provided by Attacat Internet Marketing <http://www.attacat.co.uk/>, a marketing agency based in Edinburgh. If you need similar information for your own website you can use their [free cookie audit tool](http://www.attacat.co.uk/resources/cookies).

 **Contacting us about privacy**

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, the information we have collected from you online, the practices of this site or your interaction with this website, send an email to: [info@yesScotland.net](mailto:info@yesScotland.net). You can also contact us at the address below:

Yes Scotland Ltd.  
136 Hope Street  
Glasgow  
G2 2TG

Telephone: 0141 221 4767

We will continue to evaluate our efforts to protect your information and will update our privacy policy whenever necessary.
